<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<revival>
	<modification>
		<release>Revival</release>
		<version>1.5 beta</release>
		<author>Maeyan, Malachor, Alex2069, Kite &amp; The Revival Team</release>
		<www>http://www.hellgateaus.net/</www>
		<email>maeyan.zero@gmail.com</email>
		<dependencies>
			<patch>sp_hellgate_1.10.180.3416_1.18074.70.4256</patch>
			<patch>mp_hellgate_1.10.180.3416_1.0.86.4580</patch>
		</dependencies>
		<description>Welcome to the amazing 1.5 beta release of Revival.
		This is the most expansive update to the game yet including these major features:
		* Stonehenge and Abyss Armor &amp; Weapons including original names &amp; stats.
			* 6x Stonehenge Helms, 3x Abyss Armor Sets
			* Sunblade, Sunshield, Moonblade, Gleamcarver, Dissector, Dissector Shield
			* Vigilante, Hellbore, Fry Baby, Core Magnum, Thumper, Thunderclash
			* Fire Seeds, Negatron, Singularity Node, 3x Focus Items (yes, including Slippies!)
		* Particle updates from Abyss.
		* Background environment updates from Abyss.
			* Map nodes more clearly defined.
			* Widened streets.
			* Improved architecture and enchanced geometrical detail.
			* 
		* New community item loots!
		  * 16x new unique items named after hellgateaus community members.
		* Mythic &amp; Double-Edged qualities.
		* New minigame events. When winning the minigame, you may be lucky enough to proc:
			* Palladium.
			* Fawkes items.
			* Mods.
			* Debuffs.
		* Rings added to the game.
		* 1x slot for goggles &amp; 2x slots added for your rings .
		* Passgeways are rarer but richer.
		* Rare and boss mobs are a lot more challenging and have fixed chances of dropping exceptional loot.
		* Players are rewarded with a skill &amp; attribute retrainer upon the completion of the game (norm &amp; nm).
		* Major bosses have a fixed chance of drop retrainers.
		* Moloch has been added as a rare spawn to the hell dungeon and drops original stonehenge loot.
		* A number of quest rewards have been reworked.
		* Improved dye kit colors.
		* New loader screen art work from the Abyss expansion.
		* Nanoforge increaments are larger. -something coldheart wrote into a post
		* Pets only drop from certain fixed bosses.
		* Only legendary and rarer items require identifying.
		* Nightmare mode levels scale to your character level (excluding end game).
		* Pets drop as eggs and need to be used in the cube.
		* Old bosses can be fought again.
		* Slightly better chance of finding uniques in general.
		* Obtain genre specific mods from certain enemies. ie. Get beast multiplier mods from beast type mobs.
		* Zomper, the Bill Roper zombie is now a unique spawn and carries IOU's.
		* Blue prints only craft exceptional items that require a lot of parts.
		* Mods no longer show up on weapons ?
		* None stat boosting dye kits rare drops from monsters.
		* Fix end game level advancement.
		* XP penalty removed for fighting monsters above your level.. in fact you level faster.
		* Stonehenge bosses added to end game quests, replayable.
		* Better lifetime on modifications.
		* Starting point removed. Murmur gives you skills points to advance you.
		* Tutorial dialogue can be skipped.
		* Monster shield overload capacity capped at 100%.
		* Power regeneration increase from 120 to 480.
		* Reduced power regen per Willpower from 3 to 2.
		* Monster/platyer shield charge delay reduced from 4 to 2.5 seconds.
		* Shield recharge rate from from 5% to 10%.
		* Fix reaper model.
		* Change basic crafting progressions.
		  * I'm not sure if I'm in the right place, but can I make a suggestion? It regards the Transmorg. Cube and crafting.
		
		* Lower environment visability
		
		Early game:
		* Start with no weapons in tutorial.
		* Get a choice of weapon for your first quest.
		
		
		Class changes:
		General:
		* Sprint maxes at 3 points and has no cooldown.
		* Skills rearranged into their groups.
		
		Templar:
		* Multiple auras can be used at once at the expense of mana pool.
		
		Engineer:
		* Haste bot dependency removed.
		* 
		
		Optional components:
		* Allow purchasing of retrainers.
		* Removal of regional censoring.
		* Automatically pickup basic items.
		* Malachor's Sniper Pack.
		* "Hell" mode difficulty.
		* Tabbed inventory.
		
		Previous fixes included:
		* Increased stash (x10) and inventory (2x).
		* Level cap increased to 55.
		* Destructables only drop basic items.
		* Mutant boss loots are fixed drops and scale.
		* Vendor will sometimes offer legendary mods.

		
		
		Brand new game experience. Although you can play your higher level characters, we would recommend starting a new one so you can reep the full benefits update.
		</description>
		<script type="hidden">
			<description>Extracts files from the MP data packs</description>
			<extract id="mp_hellgate_1.10.180.3416_1.0.86.4580">
				<path>data/units/items/*</path>
				<path>data/particles/*</path>
				<path>data/background/*</path>
			</extract>
		</script>
		<script type="optional">
			<description>Remove regional censoring.</description>
			<table id="items">
				<entity id="*">
					<attribute id="censorLocked">0</attribute>
					<attribute id="censorParticles">0</attribute>
					<attribute id="censorBoneShrinking">0</attribute>
					<attribute id="censorNoGore">0</attribute>
					<attribute id="censorMovies">0</attribute>
				</entity>
			</table>
		</script>
		<script type="optional">
			<description>Enable retrainers to be purchased.</description>
			<table id="treasure">
				<entity id="bodger">
					<attribute id="item06m">123</attribute>
					<attribute id="item06">12</attribute>
					<attribute id="item06z">1</attribute>
					<attribute id="item06m">123</attribute>
					<attribute id="item06">12</attribute>
					<attribute id="item06z">1</attribute>
				</entity>
			</table>
	</modification>
</revival>
