<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<revival>
	<modification id="sp_hellgate_1337_1.5.0">
		<release>Revival</release>
		<version>1.5 beta</version>
		<author>Maeyan, Malachor, Alex2069, Kite &amp; The Revival Team</author>
		<www>http://www.hellgateaus.net/</www>
		<email>maeyan.zero@gmail.com</email>
		<dependencies>
			<patch>sp_hellgate_1.10.180.3416_1.18074.70.4256</patch>
			<patch>mp_hellgate_1.10.180.3416_1.0.86.4580</patch>
		</dependencies>
		<description>Welcome to the amazing 1.5 beta release of Revival.
		
		Levels
		* Environment updates from the Abyss added.
		* Moloch spawns in Anchient Blood as a rare spawn.
		* Certain levels are now marked elite zones and enemies are much tougher.
		* Passageways and Hellriffs are a lot rarer.
		* Elite passageways contain a lot more rare monsters.
		* Treasure passageways contain a lot more loot.
		* Monster density in general increased.
		
		Players
		* Players are no longer assigned a default skill.
		* Starting attributes balanced.
		* Level cap increased to 55.
		
		Skills
		* The sprint skill caps at 4 points and no cooldown.
		
		Monsters
		* Moloch has been added into the game.
		* Champion monster scale slightly increased.
		* Champion mob health and experience increased.
		
		Quests
		* A skill point is rewarded for completing the quest Break on Through.
		
		NPCs
		* All of the original voices have been restored.
		* Techsmith 314 has been transformed into his 3rd stage state.

		Items
		* Templar items added: Sunblade, Sunshield, Moonblade, Dissector, Dissector Shield &amp; Gleamcarver.
		* 6x new unique items inspired by hellgateaus.
		* Shield overload on Swords halved and capped at 100%.
		* Boss/Mutant items are now of unique quality.
		* Boss items are fixed drops and scale.
		* Only unique retrainers can be bought and sold.
		* Rare and Legendary augmentation cost reduced.
		* Destructables only drop basic items.

		Treasure
		* Champion mobs have a better chances dropping rare loot according to monster quality.
		* Sydonai drops a skill and attribute retrainer when you finish the game.
		* Moloch drops the Stonehenge dye kits.
		* Sydonai and Moloch have a chance to drop unique retrainers.
		* Zomper drops new items.
		* Vendor modification and consumable quantities balanced.
		* Chests are generally more exciting.

		Inventory
		* Increased stash (x10) and inventory (2x).

		
		This is the most expansive update to the game yet including these major features:
		
		* 6x new Templar weapons from the Abyss and Stonehenge expansions.
		* Particle updates from Abyss.
		* Environment updates from Abyss.
		* New community item loots!
		* Mythic &amp; Double-Edged qualities.
		* New minigame events. When winning the minigame, you may be lucky enough to proc:
		* Passgeways are rarer but richer.
		* Rare and boss mobs are a lot more challenging and have fixed chances of dropping exceptional loot.
		* Players are rewarded with a skill &amp; attribute retrainer upon the completion of the game (norm &amp; nm).
		* Major bosses have a fixed chance of drop retrainers.
		* Moloch has been added as a rare spawn to the hell dungeon and drops original stonehenge loot.

		* Nanoforge increaments are larger. -something coldheart wrote into a post. dunno if its possible, but something about the nanoforge seems like it could be improved
		* Pets only drop from certain fixed bosses. - which bosses, which pets
		* Only legendary and rarer items require identifying. - need to discuss. is it a good idea. Analysers would be expensive under this implementation.
		* Nightmare mode levels scale to your character level (excluding end game).
		-------------------------------------
		It would be good if nightmare levels would generally scale to your level so you can replay any part of the game at any time.
		End game would still cap at like level 60 mobs.
		---------------------------------------
		* Pets drop as eggs and need to be used in the cube. TODO
		* Old bosses can be fought again.
		----------------------------------------
		Considering all the bosses have the same loot tables anyway (apart from their fixed mutant drops)
		I see no harm in allowing players to revist all game bosses. TODO
		----------------------------------------
		* Slightly better chance of finding uniques in general. TODO
		* Obtain genre specific mods from certain enemies. ie. Get beast multiplier mods from beast type mobs.TODO
		* Zomper, the Bill Roper zombie is now a unique spawn and carries IOU's.
		---------------------------
		Zomper created. Needs to be enabled as a unique type spawn so he can spawn anywhere.
		Needs loot table and items
		------------------------
		* Blue prints only craft exceptional items that require a lot of parts. TODO
		* Mods no longer show up on weapons ?
		----------------------------
		We can disable mods from showing up. Should we do it? We can't fix them but we can stop them from showing up
		--------------------------
		* None stat boosting dye kits rare drops from monsters. TODO
		* XP penalty removed for fighting monsters above your level.. in fact you level slightly faster. TODO
		* Stonehenge bosses added to end game quests, replayable.
		---------------------------------
		Add these bosses to St Pauls quests, allow repeating. Make them hard
		-------------------------------------
		* Better lifetime on modifications.
		-----
		Modification generally last about 12 levels. We could make them last 20 levels
		-----
		* Starting point removed. Murmur gives you skills points to advance you. TODO
		* Tutorial dialogue can be skipped. TODO
		* Monster shield overload capacity capped at 100%. TODO
		* Power regeneration increase from 120 to 480. TODO
		* Reduced power regen per Willpower from 3 to 2. TODO
		* Monster/platyer shield charge delay reduced from 4 to 2.5 seconds. TODO
		* Shield recharge rate from from 5% to 10%. TODO
		* Fix reaper model.
		------------------------------
		A lot of people want to change the quest that uses a shock fiend monster, when to be consistant with the story line it should be the reaper.
		-----------------------------
		* Change basic crafting progressions.
		-----------------------------
		A lot of recipies can be added for general fun. Ie, 2 lower level injectors turn into a higher
		-------------------------------
		* Lower environment visability. TODO try darken the game
		
		Early game:
		* Start with no weapons in tutorial. TODO
		* Get a choice of weapon for your first quest. ie. Do you want to go a one or two hand build? Fire or toxic? etc TODO
		--------------------
		A lot of severe gameplay changes. We can make the game a lot of fun, it will take a lot of time.
		List all ideas here and current status.
		--------------------
		
		Class changes:
		General:
		* Sprint maxes at 3 points and has no cooldown. TODO
		* Skills rearranged into their groups. TODO. Should we bother
		
		Templar:
		* Multiple auras can be used at once at the expense of mana pool. TODO
		
		Engineer:
		* Haste bot dependency removed. // Saw this in a community mod. Is it a good idea
		* 
		
		Optional components:
		* Allow purchasing of retrainers. TODO
		* Removal of regional censoring. 
		* Automatically pickup basic items.
		* Malachor's Sniper Pack.
		* "Hell" mode difficulty.
		* Tabbed inventory.
		

		
		Brand new game experience. Although you can play your higher level characters, we would recommend starting a new one so you can reep the full benefits update.
		</description>
		<script type="hidden">
			<description>Extracts files from the MP data packs</description>
			<extract id="mp_hellgate_1.10.180.3416_1.0.86.4580">
				<path>data/units/items/*</path>
				<path>data/particles/*</path>
				<path>data/background/*</path>
				<path>data/states/*</path>
				<path>data/ai/*</path>
				<path>data/lighting/*</path>
			</extract>
		</script>
		<script type="optional">
			<description>Remove regional censoring.</description>
			<table id="items">
				<entity id="*">
					<attribute id="censorLocked">0</attribute>
					<attribute id="censorParticles">0</attribute>
					<attribute id="censorBoneShrinking">0</attribute>
					<attribute id="censorNoGore">0</attribute>
					<attribute id="censorMovies">0</attribute>
				</entity>
			</table>
		</script>
		<script type="optional">
			<description>Enable retrainers to be purchased.</description>
			<table id="treasure">
				<entity id="bodger">
					<attribute id="item06m">123</attribute>
					<attribute id="item06">12</attribute>
					<attribute id="item06z">1</attribute>
					<attribute id="item06m">123</attribute>
					<attribute id="item06">12</attribute>
					<attribute id="item06z">1</attribute>
				</entity>
			</table>
		</script>
	</modification>
</revival>
