<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<revival>
	<modification>
		<release>Revival</release>
		<version>1.5 beta</release>
		<author>Maeyan, Malachor, Alex2069, Kite &amp; The Revival Team</release>
		<www>http://www.hellgateaus.net/</www>
		<email>maeyan.zero@gmail.com</email>
		<dependencies>
			<patch>sp_hellgate_1.10.180.3416_1.18074.70.4256</patch>
			<patch>mp_hellgate_1.10.180.3416_1.0.86.4580</patch>
		</dependencies>
		<description>Welcome to the amazing 1.5 beta release of Revival.
		This is the most expansive update to the game yet including these major features:
		
		
		* Stonehenge and Abyss Armor &amp; Weapons including original names &amp; stats.
			* 6x Stonehenge Helms, 3x Abyss Armor Sets
			* Sunblade, Sunshield, Moonblade, Gleamcarver, Dissector, Dissector Shield
			* Vigilante, Hellbore, Fry Baby, Core Magnum, Thumper, Thunderclash
			* Fire Seeds, Negatron, Singularity Node, 3x Focus Items (yes, including Slippies!)
			
			
			----------------------
		29/09/10: The stonehenge helms have been added but are not rendored correctly. It could possably be
		a problem with the blend operation.
		
		As for the Abyss sets, The bottom half of the set rendors okay, but the hands, shoulders and chest suffer
		geometrical distortion. I am quite sure it isn't a differation in the .am data structure but possible
		error with blend operation again. The helms are off centre like the stonehenge ones.
		
		All of the Templar swords and shields work okay. The slot props need updating and also the shield, armor
		and damage props.
		
		All of the other weapons are not implemented properly yet and need a lot of work. Some weapons require
		skill imports too which have yet to be done.
			----------------------
			
		* Particle updates from Abyss. - Nothing to be done.
		* Background environment updates from Abyss.- Nothing to be done.
		* New community item loots!
		  * 16x new unique items named after hellgateaus community members.
		  ------------------------
		These items have been started, need testing and others still need adding.
		  ------------------------
			
		* Mythic &amp; Double-Edged qualities.
		  ------------------------
			The affixes have been added to the affix table but all the props need changing
			because the symbols are different in the TC version.
			------------------------
		
		
		* New minigame events. When winning the minigame, you may be lucky enough to proc:
			* Palladium.
			* Fawkes items.
			* Mods.
			* Debuffs.
			-------------------------
			The treasure classes have been templated, needs implementing and testing.
			-------------------------
			
		* Rings added to the game.
		* 1x slot for goggles &amp; 2x slots added for your rings .
		  -------------------------
			Issue: The ring slots are highlighted when equipping weapons.
		  --------------------------
		
		
		* Passgeways are rarer but richer. TODO. Need to change the spawn chance in levels and tweak the passageway multipliers.
		* Rare and boss mobs are a lot more challenging and have fixed chances of dropping exceptional loot.
		  --------------------------------
		The treasure classes have been implemented and added to the monster quality table. Needs testing\
		These mobs still need toughening
		-----------------------------------
		
		* Players are rewarded with a skill &amp; attribute retrainer upon the completion of the game (norm &amp; nm).
		----------------------------------------
		Treasure table created, need to link to sydonai first time look table.
		------------------------------------------
		
		* Major bosses have a fixed chance of drop retrainers.
		----------------------------------------------
		Sydonai and Moloch only. These are the unique retrainer drops.
		The unique retrainers have been added as new items. Note the difference between the normal and unique retrainers. Only the unique retrainers can be bought/sold. 
		------------------------------------------------
		* Moloch has been added as a rare spawn to the hell dungeon and drops original stonehenge loot.
		-------------------------------
		Loot tables created. Still needs work
		----------------------------------
		* A number of quest rewards have been reworked. 
		TODO. this will be a lot of work. We should perhaps only tweak a small number of quests for now and put a lot of thought and creativity into the rewards.
		----------------------------------
		* Improved dye kit colors.
		------------------------------------
		I'm using sets designed by a forum member, will probably need more. TODO
		-------------------------------------
		* New loader screen art work from the Abyss expansion. - CODEX is onto this
		* Nanoforge increaments are larger. -something coldheart wrote into a post. dunno if its possible, but something about the nanoforge seems like it could be improved
		* Pets only drop from certain fixed bosses. - which bosses, which pets
		* Only legendary and rarer items require identifying. - need to discuss. is it a good idea. Analysers would be expensive under this implementation.
		* Nightmare mode levels scale to your character level (excluding end game).
		-------------------------------------
		It would be good if nightmare levels would generally scale to your level so you can replay any part of the game at any time.
		End game would still cap at like level 60 mobs.
		---------------------------------------
		* Pets drop as eggs and need to be used in the cube. TODO
		* Old bosses can be fought again.
		----------------------------------------
		Considering all the bosses have the same loot tables anyway (apart from their fixed mutant drops)
		I see no harm in allowing players to revist all game bosses. TODO
		----------------------------------------
		* Slightly better chance of finding uniques in general. TODO
		* Obtain genre specific mods from certain enemies. ie. Get beast multiplier mods from beast type mobs.TODO
		* Zomper, the Bill Roper zombie is now a unique spawn and carries IOU's.
		---------------------------
		Zomper created. Needs to be enabled as a unique type spawn so he can spawn anywhere.
		Needs loot table and items
		------------------------
		* Blue prints only craft exceptional items that require a lot of parts. TODO
		* Mods no longer show up on weapons ?
		----------------------------
		We can disable mods from showing up. Should we do it? We can't fix them but we can stop them from showing up
		--------------------------
		* None stat boosting dye kits rare drops from monsters. TODO
		* XP penalty removed for fighting monsters above your level.. in fact you level slightly faster. TODO
		* Stonehenge bosses added to end game quests, replayable.
		---------------------------------
		Add these bosses to St Pauls quests, allow repeating. Make them hard
		-------------------------------------
		* Better lifetime on modifications.
		-----
		Modification generally last about 12 levels. We could make them last 20 levels
		-----
		* Starting point removed. Murmur gives you skills points to advance you. TODO
		* Tutorial dialogue can be skipped. TODO
		* Monster shield overload capacity capped at 100%. TODO
		* Power regeneration increase from 120 to 480. TODO
		* Reduced power regen per Willpower from 3 to 2. TODO
		* Monster/platyer shield charge delay reduced from 4 to 2.5 seconds. TODO
		* Shield recharge rate from from 5% to 10%. TODO
		* Fix reaper model.
		------------------------------
		A lot of people want to change the quest that uses a shock fiend monster, when to be consistant with the story line it should be the reaper.
		-----------------------------
		* Change basic crafting progressions.
		-----------------------------
		A lot of recipies can be added for general fun. Ie, 2 lower level injectors turn into a higher
		-------------------------------
		* Lower environment visability. TODO try darken the game
		
		Early game:
		* Start with no weapons in tutorial. TODO
		* Get a choice of weapon for your first quest. ie. Do you want to go a one or two hand build? Fire or toxic? etc TODO
		--------------------
		A lot of severe gameplay changes. We can make the game a lot of fun, it will take a lot of time.
		List all ideas here and current status.
		--------------------
		
		Class changes:
		General:
		* Sprint maxes at 3 points and has no cooldown. TODO
		* Skills rearranged into their groups. TODO. Should we bother
		
		Templar:
		* Multiple auras can be used at once at the expense of mana pool. TODO
		
		Engineer:
		* Haste bot dependency removed. // Saw this in a community mod. Is it a good idea
		* 
		
		Optional components:
		* Allow purchasing of retrainers. TODO
		* Removal of regional censoring. 
		* Automatically pickup basic items.
		* Malachor's Sniper Pack.
		* "Hell" mode difficulty.
		* Tabbed inventory.
		
		Previous fixes included:
		* Increased stash (x10) and inventory (2x).
		* Level cap increased to 55.
		* Destructables only drop basic items.
		* Mutant boss loots are fixed drops and scale.
		* Vendor will sometimes offer legendary mods. Increase mod offering from 6 to 8.

		
		
		Brand new game experience. Although you can play your higher level characters, we would recommend starting a new one so you can reep the full benefits update.
		</description>
		<script type="hidden">
			<description>Extracts files from the MP data packs</description>
			<extract id="mp_hellgate_1.10.180.3416_1.0.86.4580">
				<path>data/units/items/*</path>
				<path>data/particles/*</path>
				<path>data/background/*</path>
			</extract>
		</script>
		<script type="optional">
			<description>Remove regional censoring.</description>
			<table id="items">
				<entity id="*">
					<attribute id="censorLocked">0</attribute>
					<attribute id="censorParticles">0</attribute>
					<attribute id="censorBoneShrinking">0</attribute>
					<attribute id="censorNoGore">0</attribute>
					<attribute id="censorMovies">0</attribute>
				</entity>
			</table>
		</script>
		<script type="optional">
			<description>Enable retrainers to be purchased.</description>
			<table id="treasure">
				<entity id="bodger">
					<attribute id="item06m">123</attribute>
					<attribute id="item06">12</attribute>
					<attribute id="item06z">1</attribute>
					<attribute id="item06m">123</attribute>
					<attribute id="item06">12</attribute>
					<attribute id="item06z">1</attribute>
				</entity>
			</table>
	</modification>
</revival>
